

# **Abhijeet Kamble**

Presales Engineer

## **Profile**

Total work experience of 10 years and I have ambition To work in an organization where I use my skills and knowledge to deliver value added results as well as further enhance my learning and develop my career in the field of INSTRUMENTATION /Electronic Security Industry.

## **Contact**

- +91 9930072354
- abhijeetabk10@gmail.com
- E-402, Platina, CBG, Palava City, Dombivali (E) Maharashtra, 421204

## Skills

- IP/Analog CCTV
- Access Control System
- Fire Alarm System
- Public Address System
- Intrusion Alarm System
- Rodent Repellent System
- E- Tendering
- Proposal
- RFQ/RFI
- BOQ/BOM

# **Education**

(2008-2012)

#### **SAVITRIBAI PHULE PUNE VIDYAPEETH**

Bachelor of Engineering - Instrumentation & control

# **Experience**

## (2022- present)

#### **BHATIA BROTHERS FZE**

Pre-Qualification Engineer

- Review tender/RFQ/RFI/Proposal document of IP CCTV, Access Control System, PA system ETC.
- Determine the proposed product and scope in consultation with Sales, Design Department and Technical team.
- Prepare bill of material, purchase specification of bought out items
- Liaise with procurement team and supplier and secure Quote.
- Review supplier's proposal and provide comments/ Secure correct quote.
- Ensure that Clients pricing and technical tender schedules are complete and accurate.
- Organize Budget Handover Meetings to Project Managers
- Review technical part of quotation to client and ensure it is in line with costing and technical specification.
- Fill up technical specification sheet of tender document.
- All in-house co-ordination for preparation of bid including follow-up, collection of input from various sub-contractors or 3rd party. Preparing as well as review Variation of requisition (VOR) for additional/deletion scope of work during execution of project.

# **Personnel Information**

- DOB: 10/10/1985
- Passport No. J7002193
- Languages Known:
  - 1. English
- · 2. Hindi
- 3. Marathi
- · 4. German (Learning)

# **Experience**

## (2020-2022)

## SAMARTH SECURITY SYSTEMS (I) PVT. LTD.

Pre-sales Engineer

- Review tender/RFQ/RFI/Proposal document of IP CCTV, Access Control System, PA system ETC.
- Determine the proposed product and scope in consultation with Sales, Design Department and Technical team.
- Prepare bill of material, purchase specification of bought out items
- Liaise with procurement team and supplier and secure Quote.
- Review supplier's proposal and provide comments/ Secure correct quote.
- Ensure that Clients pricing and technical tender schedules are complete and accurate.
- Organize Budget Handover Meetings to Project Managers
- Review technical part of quotation to client and ensure it is in line with costing and technical specification.
- Fill up technical specification sheet of tender document.
- All in-house co-ordination for preparation of bid including follow-up, collection of input from various sub-contractors or 3rd party. Preparing as well as review Variation of requisition (VOR) for additional/deletion scope of work during execution of project.

# (2018-2020)

#### **FEURMANN LLP**

Techno-commercial engineer

- Review tender/enquiry/Proposal document of CCTV/ACS/FAS ETC.
- Determine the proposed product and scope in consultation with Sales, Design Department and Technical team.
- Prepare bill of material, purchase specification of bought out items
- Arrangement of Project Engineers and Technicians for projects and AMC for PAN India
- Review supplier's proposal and provide comments/Secure correct quote.

- Ensure that Clients pricing and technical tender schedules are complete and accurate.
- Organize Budget Handover Meetings to Project Managers
- Review technical part of quotation to client and ensure it is in line with costing and technical specification.
- Fill up technical specification sheet of tender document.

# (2017-2018)

#### **OMNITEC SECURITY SYSTEMS**

Sr. Project Engineer

- Interact daily with the clients and technicians to interpret their needs and requirements and represent them in the field of CCTV & Parking Management System.
- Ensure that Clients pricing and technical tender schedules are complete and accurate.
- Organize Budget Handover Meetings to Project
- Managers
- Review technical part of quotation to client and ensure it is in line with costing and technical specification.
- Fill up technical specification sheet of tender document.
- To Perform overall quality control of the work (budget,
- schedule, plans, personnel's performance) and report regularly on project status under submission-online/
- physical, client meeting, arrangement of meeting,
- Verification, FAT,SAT etc.
- Cooperate and communicate effectively with project
- Managers and other project participants to provide assistance and technical support
- Review engineering deliverables and initiate Appropriate corrective actions.

# (2016-2017)

#### **SOLUS SECURITY SYSTEMS**

**Project Engineer** 

- Interact daily with the clients and technicians to interpret their needs and requirements and represent them in the field of ACS, CCTV, FAS ETC.
- Ensure that Clients pricing and technical tender schedules are complete and accurate.

- Organize Budget Handover Meetings to Project Managers
- Review technical part of quotation to client and ensure it is in line with costing and technical specification.
- Fill up technical specification sheet of tender document.
- To Perform overall quality control of the work (budget,
- schedule, plans, personnel's performance) and report regularly on project status under submission-online/
- physical, client meeting, arrangement of meeting,
- Verification, FAT,SAT etc.
- Cooperate and communicate effectively with project
- Managers and other project participants to provide assistance and technical support
- Review engineering deliverables and initiate Appropriate corrective actions.

# (2013-2016)

## **ASCENT NETWORKS PVT. LTD.**

## Project Assistant

- Finding Tenders of CCTV, ACCESS CONTROL SYSTEM, FIRE ALARM SYSTEM, GAS DETECTORS, EPABX, NETWORKING, IT- SERVER, STORAGE, CABLING -ACTIVE, PASSIVE ETC. from websites or Physically.
- Proposals, Attending pre-bid meeting, Technical bid opening, price bid opening, formation of datasheets, tender docs, checklists, Preparation of BOM, , BOQ, Proposal, Estimation Etc.
- Tender submission-online/physical, client meeting, arrangement of meeting, Verification, FAT,SAT etc.
- Go on site for project status, documents verification and Main role is to assist Sr. Project Engg.
- Perform overall quality control of the work (budget, schedule, plans, and personnel's performance) and report regularly on project status.